The Carleton Hodge collection: books from the library of Carleton Hodge Z7770 .H6
Lilly Library
- B (Box 28)
  - Bible. Saint Joseph edition of the new American bible translated from the original languages with critical use of all the ancient sources by Members of the Catholic Biblical Association of America. ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Co., 1970 (Box 49)
  - Bible. Holy Bible revised standard version containing the old and new testaments with the Apocrypha/Deuterocanonical books and ecumenical edition. New York, Glasgow, London, Toronto, Sydney, Auckland: Collins, 1971-1973 (Old Testament t.p. has date 1973; New testament t.p. dated 1971 second edition) (Box 6)
  - Bible. Holy Bible illustrated containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared and revised King James version 1611. Pleasantville, New York: Reader's Digest Association, Inc., 1971 (Box 1)
  - Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures rendered from the original languages by the new world bible translation committee -- revised 1971 c.e. -- New York?: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York, Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association (Box 23)
  - Bible. King James II version of the bible. Grand Rapids, MI: Associated Publishers and Authos Inc., 1971 (on verso of t.p. second edition) (Box 26)
  - Bible. American standard bible text edition. Carol Stream, Ill.: Creation House, Inc., 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bible. Holy Bible old and new testaments in the King James version translated out of the original tongues and with previous translations diligently compared and revised self-pronouncing. Nashville: Camden: New York: Thomas Nelson, Publishers., 1972 (Box 25)
  - Bible. Holy Bible in four translations. King James version -- New American standard bible -- New English bible -- The Jerusalem bible. New York: Iversen-Norman Associates, 1972 (also on Front of t.p. World-Wide Publications) (Box 41)
  - Bible. Living Bible Holman illustrated edition paraphrased with 550 full color illustrations including 53 maps and charts. Philadelphia: New York: A.J. Holman Company, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Bible. New American standard bible. Carol Stream, IL: Creation House, Inc., 1973 (Box 26)
  - Bible. Special English-German edition The Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments and English text -- The Authorized King James Version German translation of Dr. Martin Luther with references and maps. Aylmer, Ontario and LaGrange, IN: Pathway Publishers, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Bible. Bible in order all the writings which make up the bible, arranged in their chronological order according to the dates at which they were written, or edited into the form in which we know them; seen against the history of the times, as the bible provides it. With introductions and notes Edited by Joseph Rhymer Jerusalem bible version. London: Darton, Longman & Todd, 1975 (Box 52)
  - Bible. Interlinear bible Hebrew/English. Jay P. Green, Sr. ed. Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Book House, 1976-1983 (Box 22)
    - v. I Genesis - Ruth, 1976 (Box 22)
    - v. II Samuel - Psalm 55, 1976 (Box 22)
    - v. III Psalm 56 - Malachi, 1978 (Box 22)
    - v. III Psalm 56 - Malachi, 1983 (Box 22)
    - v. IV New Testament, 1979 (Box 22)
  - Bible. New English bible with the Apocrypha Oxford study edition. Samuel Sandmel general editor... New York: Oxford University Press, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Bible. New American bible translated from the original languages with critical use of all the ancient sources by members of the Catholic Biblical Association of America Sponsored by the Bishops' committee of the Confraternity of Christian Doctrine. Nashville, TN: Memorial Bibles International, Inc.Bible in cedar box., 1976 (Box 54)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments with the apocryphal/Deutercanonical books new revised standard edition. New York and Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Bible. Andrew's Holy Bible for the layman -- Dallas: B and B Foundations, Inc., 1977 (Box 37)
  - Bible. Holy Bible new international version containing the old and new testaments. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Bible Publishers, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Bible. Holy Bible the new King James version containing the old and new testaments. Carmel, N.Y.: Guideposts, 1982 (Box 26)
  - Bible. Reader's digest bible condensed from the revised standard version old and new testaments General editor Bruce M. Metzger... Pleasentville, N.Y., London, Montreal, Sydney, Cape Town, Hong Kong: Reader Digest Association, 1982 (Box 43)
  - Bible. King James version The Reese chronological bible the authorized edition of the original work by Edward Reese. Minneapolis, MN: Bethany House Publishers, 1982 (Box 50)
  - Bible. Possibility thinkers bible. The new King James version positive verses for possibility thinking highlighted in blue. Nashville, Camden, New York: Thomas Nelson Publishers, 1984 (Box 48)
  - Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures with references rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- revised 1984 -- Brooklyn, N.Y.: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc. (Box 48)
  - Bible. St. Jerome edition the catholic study bible today's English version with Deutercanonicals/Apocrypha. Nashville: Camden: New York: Catholic Bible Press a division of Thomas Nelson Publishers, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Bible. New Jerusalem Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1985 (Box 52)
  - Bible. New world translation of the Holy Scriptures rendered from the original languages by the new world translation committe -- revised 1984 -- Brooklyn, N.Y.: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York, Inc. International Bible Students Association, [1986] (Box 26)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command authorized King James Version with explanatory notes and cross references to the standard works of the church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints. Salt Lake City: Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Bible. Webster bible. Grand Rapids, MI, Baker Book House, 1987 (Box 50)
  - Bible. Holy Bible international children's bible new century version. Dallas, London, Sydney, Singapore: Word Publishing, 1988 (Box 22)
  - Bible. Everyday Bible New Century Version clearly translated for life. Carmel, N.Y.: Guideposts, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Bible. Catholic one year bible arranged in 365 daily readings the living bible a thought-for-thought translation with Deuterocanonical Books. Wheaton, IL: Tyndale House Publishers, Inc., and Huntington, IN: Our Sunday Visitor Publishing Division, 1988 (Box 35)
  - Bible. Holy Bible contemporary English version. New York: American Bible Society, 1995 (Box 25)
  - Bible. Selections. Stepping stones -- the complete bible narratives brought together chronologically in the text of the King James version edited and arranged by John Thomas Clark. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1954 (Box 42)
  - Bible. Selections. Reader's bible a narrative selections from the King James version edited with an introduction and ntoes by Roland Mushat Frye. Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1965 (Box 42)
  - Bible. O.T.? (Beginning of title in Greek) ... vetus testamentum, ex versione septuaginta interpretum. Juxta exemplar vaticanum, ex editione holmesh et Lamberti Bos. Tom .I Glasguæ: Ex Prelo Academico; Impenis Rivingtons & Cochran, Longman, Hurst & Soc., G. & W. B. Whittaker, R. Priestley, Et. G. Cowie & Soc., Londini: Bell & Bradfute, Et. A. Black, Edinburgi, 1822 (Box 31)
    - Tom. I (Box 31)
    - Tom. II (Box 31)
  - Bible. O.T. Collateral Bible; or, A key to the Holy Scriptures: in which all the corresponding texts are brought together in one view, and arranged in a familiar and easy manner. Philadelphia, John Lavel and Samuel F. Bradford, 1826-1829 (Box 2)
    - v.II, pt.I whole number 5;-- in paper wrappers, 1827 (Box 2)
    - v.II, pt.III? whole number 7;-- in paper wrappers, 1828 (Box 2)
    - v.II, pt.IV whole number 8;-- in paper wrappers, 1828 (Box 2)
    - v.III, pt.II whole number 11 -- in paper wrappers (Box 2)
    - v.III, pt.? bottom of wrapper gone (Box 2)
    - [v.1?] Philadelphia, Samuel F. Bradford-- bound, 1826 (Box 2)
    - v.III; -- bound, 1828 (Box 2)
    - [?] no t.p. -- bound (Box 2)
  - Bible. O.T. Old testament, arranged in historical and chronological order, (on the basis of Lightfoot's chronicle) in such a manner, that the books, chapters, psalms, prophecies, &c. &c. may be read as one connected history, in the words of the authorized translation. With notes and copious indexes. By the Rev. George Townsent, M.A. ... Boston: Perkins and Marvin and Philadelphia: Henry Perkins, 1838 (Box 50)
  - Bible. O.T. (lacks title page from Genesis to Job) [S.l.: s.n., 1850-?] (Box 31)
  - Bible. O.T. Old Testament a new translation by James Moffatt D.D., D.Litt., M.A. (Oxon) Vol.I Genesis - Esther. London: Hodder and Stoughton, [1923] (Date from note by Hodge) (Box 25)
  - Bible. O.T. Old testament a new translation by James Moffatt D.D., D.Litt., M.A. (Oxon) Vol.II Job - Malachi. London: Hodder and Stoughton, [1924] (Date from note by Hodge) (Box 25)
  - Bible. O.T. Old testament an American translation by Alexander R. Gordon, Theophile J. Meek, J.M. Powis Smith, Leroy Waterman Edited by J.M. Powis Smith. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1927 (Box 25)
  - Bible. O.T. Holy Bible the old testament Volume I, Genesis - Nehemiah revised standard version translated from the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 ... Toronto: New York: Edinburgh: Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1952 (Box 25)
  - Bible. O.T. Holy Bible the old testament Volume II, Esther - Malachi revised standard version translated from the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 ... Toronto: New York: Edinburg: Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1952 (Box 25)
  - Bible. O.T. Old testament authorized catholic edition abridged from the holy bible sponsored by the Episcopal Committee of the Confraternity of Chritian Doctrine ... New York: Guild Press, 1963 (Box 42)
  - Bible. O.T. Old testament complete with annotations by Rev. Joseph A. Grispino, S.M., S.S.L. The text is the new translation sponsored by the Episcopal Committee of the Confraternity of Christian Doctrine for the books Genesis to Ruth, Job to Sirach, ... New York: Guild Press, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Bible. O.T. Old testament of the Jerusalem Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1966 (Box 23)
  - Bible. O.T. New English bible the Apocrypha. Lower half of t.p. missing. On verso of t.p. Delegates of the Oxford University Press and the Syndics of the Cambridge University Press, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Bible. O.T. (Beg. of t.p. is in Hebrew) Biblia Hebraica Stuttgartensia quae antea cooperantibus A.Alt, O. Eißfeldt, P. Kahle ediderat R. Kittel Editio funditus renovata ... Stuttgart: Deutsche Biblegesellschaft, 1976/77 (Box 41)
  - Bible. O.T. Good news bible today's English version old testament. New York: American Bible Society, 1978 (Box 52)
  - Bible. O.T. Konkordanz zum Hebraischen alten testament nach dem von Paul Kahle in der Biblia Hebraica edidit Rudolf Kittel besorgten Masoretischen Text ... Zweite Auflage. Stuttgart: Deutsche Bibelgesllschaft, 1981 (Box 42)
  - Bible. O.T. Genesis. First book of Moses called Genesis. Yellow Springs: OH: Kahoe and company(no. 29 of 950)., 1929 (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Genesis. Book of Beginnings a new translation of the Book of Genesis with special attention to its poetic values. By Alexander Marlowe. Grand Rapids, MI: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Company, 1938 (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Genesis. Path through Genesis by Bruce Vawter, C.M. New York: Sheed & Ward, 1965 (Box 27)
  - Bible. O.T. Genesis. In the Beginning a new English rendition of the book of Genesis translated with commentary and notes by Everett Fox. New York: Schocken Books, 1983 (Box 27)
  - Bible. O.T. Exodus. Now these are the names a new English rendition of the Book of Exodus translated with commentary and notes by Everett Fox. New York: Schocken Books, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Bible. O.T. Samuel I. & II. Books of I. & II. Samuel, translated out of the original Hebrew: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command. Oxford: Printed at the University Press for the British and Foreign Bible Society, 1896 (Box 52)
  - Bible. O.T. Kings I & II. Books of I. & II. Kings, translated out of the original Hebrew: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command. Oxford: Printed at the University Press for the British and Foreign Bible Society, 1896 (Box 52)
  - Bible. O.T. Psalms. Psalms in modern speech and rhythmical form by John mcFadyen, D.D. ... Third edition. London: James Clarke & Co., [1917-1945?] (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Psalms. Psalms for the modern man today's English version. New York: American Bible Society, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Bible. O.T. Song of Solomon. Song of songs translated from the original Hebrew with an introduction and explanations by Hugh J. Schonfield, D.S. LITT. [S.l.]: New American Library, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Proverbs. Proverbs. New York: American Bible Society, [1900-1980?] (Box 56)
  - Bible. O.T. Ecclesiastes. Ecclesiastes with an essay by Irwin Edman. New York: Odyssey Press, 1946 (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Isaiah. Isaiah in modern speech by John Edgar McFadyen, D.D. ... second impression. London: James Clarke & Co., [1918] (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Isaiah. Book of the prophet Isaiah, translated out of the original Hebrew; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. London: British and Foreign Bible Society printed at the Cambridge University Press, 1920 (Box 52)
  - Bible. O.T. Isaiah. Book of Isaiah from the new international version. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Bible Publishers, 1975 (Box 55)
  - Bible. O.T. Jeremiah and Lamentations. Book of Jeremiah including the Lamentations with fifteen drawings in black and white by William Saphier. New York: Privately Printed by Nicholas BrownReview copy of 975 printed., 1921 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title page in Greek) ... Novum Testamentum Graece ex recenione Jo. Jac. Greisbachii cum selecta lectionum varietate. Tomus Primus. Lipsiae: Sumtibus G.J. Cöschen[Lacking both covers], 1805 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. Bible. Neue testament unser Herrn und Heilandes Jesu Christi, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers. Mit kurzen inhalt eines jeden capitels, und ... Fünfte Auflage. Germantaun: Michael Billmener, 1808 (Box 29)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: Translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. London: Stereotyped for the Bible Society at Philadelphia by T. Rutt2 copies., 1812 (Box 15)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, Newly Translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Mathew Carey, 1813 (Box 14)
  - Bible. N.T. Novum testamentum domini nostri Jesu Christi, ob frequentes omnium interpretationum hallucinations, nunc demum ex codice Alexandrino, adhibitis etiam compulribus mss. Variantibusque lectionibus editis, summa fide ac cura Latine Redditum. ... Londini: Typis Schulze et Dean, Prostat apud J. Bohn, 1817 (Box 38)
  - Bible. N.T. Apocryphal New Testament, being all the Gospels, Epistles, and other pieces now extant, attributed in the first four centuries to Jesus Christ, his apostles, and their companions, and not included in the New Testament by its compilers. translated from the original tongues, and now first collected into one volume. London: Printed for William Hone, 1820 (Box 38)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title page in Greek. Title page is also torn) ... Greek according to Griesbach; the English upon the basis of the fourth London edition of the improved Version, with an attempt to further improvement from the translations of Campbell, Wakefield, Scarlett, Macknight and Thomoson. In two volumes. By Abner Kneeland, ... Vol. II. Philadelphia: Published by the Editor, no. 31 ... William Fry, Printer, 1823 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, Newly Translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Samuel Wood and Sons and Samuel S. Woods & Co. in Baltimore, 1825 (Box 15)
  - Bible. N.T. Scientia Biblica: containing the new testament, in the original tongue, with the English vulgate, and a copious and original collection of parallel passages, printed in words at length in three volumes. London: W. Booth, 1825 (Box 21)
    - v.1 (Box 21)
    - v.2 (Box 21)
    - v.3 (Box 21)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... Novum testamentum Graece. Recognovit atque insignioris lectionum varietatis et argumentorum notations subiunxit Gerog. Christian. Knappius. Tomus I complectens quatuor evangelia. Editio Quarta. Halis Saxonum: E. Libraria Orphanotrophei, 1829 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Printed and Published by William F. Geddes, 1831 (Box 12)
  - Bible. N.T. Clavis Novi Testamenti philological usibus scholarum et iuvenum theologiae studiosorum accommodata auctore Christiano Abrahamo Wahl, ... editio minor. Lipsiae: Joh. Ambrosium Barth, 1831 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... novum testamentum, cum versione Latina Ariæ Montani, in quo tum selecti versiculi 1900, ... auctore Johanne Leusden, New York: Stereotyped by Hammond Wallis & Co. Published by Collins & Hannay(Spine title: Leusden's Gr. & Lat. Testament)., 1831 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. Novi testamenti libri historici Græce. Textui recepto appsitæ sunt lections griesbachianæ. Cum commentaries D. Christiani Theophili Kuinoel, ... Londini: Jos. Booker, 1835 (Box 21)
    - Tomus 1 (Box 21)
    - Tomus 2 (Box 21)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: G.W. Mentz, 1836 (Box 12)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Joseph McDowell, 183? (date from note by Hodge) (Box 12)
  - Bible. N.T. Novum testamentum Graece Post Ioh. Aug. Henr. Tittmannum Olim Prof. Lips. Ad Fidem Optimorum librorum secundis curis recognovit lectionumque varietatem notavit Augustus Hahn in Acad. Vratisl. Prof. Editio Americana stereotypa curante Edvardo Robinson, S.T.D. Neo-Eboraci: Sumtibus et typis Leavitt et Trow and Bostoniae: Apud Crocker et Brewster, 1835 (Box 21)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Stereotype edition. New York: Stereotyped by A. Chandler for the American Bible Society, 1838 (Box 51)
  - Bible. N.T. Polyglott school testament the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: with the marginal readings, compendious annotations, and the copious references to parallel and illustrative passages. Keene, N.H.: J. & J.W. Prentiss, 1840 (Box 2)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Thomas Sutton, 1842 (Box 2)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society(Also in German parallel columns and a German t.p.), 1849 (Box 40)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. Translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1850 (Box 54)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1854 (Box 52)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) Novum testamentum ad exemplar millianum, cum emendationibus et lectionibus Griesbachii, præcipuis vocibus ellipticis, thematibus ominum vocum difficiliorum, atque locis scripturæ parallelis. Studio et Labore Gulielmi Greenfield. ... Philadelphia: H.C. Peck & Theo. Bliss., [1856?] (Box 50)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1857 (Box 11)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible SocietyIn 4 vols. Only v.1 has t.p. rest of vols are continuously paged., 1857 (Box 54)
    - 1. St. Matthew - St. Mark p. 180 (Box 54)
    - 2. St. Luke - St. John p. 181-382 (Box 54)
    - 3. Acts I - I Corinthians p. 383-572 (Box 54)
    - missing v. 4 (Box 54)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1860 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Savioiur Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1861 (Box 54)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament, from the family bible: with brief notes and instructions, designed to give the results of critical investigation. and to assist common readers to understand the meaning of the Holy Spirit in the inspired word. ... New York: American Tract Society, 1862 (Box 4)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... nove testamentum Graece e codice vaticano edit Valentinus Lock, SS. Theologiae Doctor et Professor in Lyceo Amvergensi. Ratisbonae: Typis ac Sumptibus Georgh Joseph Manz, 1862 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... novum testamentum, cum versione Latina Ariæ Montani, in quo tum selecti versiculi 1900, ... auctore Johanne Leusden, Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co(Spine title: Leusden's Greek & Latin Testament), 1863 (Box 31)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1863 (Box 54)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament: the authorized English version; with introduction, and various readings from the three most celebrated manuscripts of the original Greek text. by Constantine Tischendorf. Tauchnitz edition, volume 1000. Leipzig: Bernard Tauchnitz, 1869 (Box Box before 25)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament: translated from the Greek text of Tischendorf, by George R. Noyes, D. D. ... Boston: American Unitarian Association, 1869 (Box 54)
  - Bible. N.T. Neue Testament unsers herrn heilanders Jesu Christi, nach der Deutschen uebersetzung Doctor Martin Luthers. Mit kurzen inhalt eines jeden Capitels, ... Lancaster: Johann Bär's Göhnen, 1871 (Box 40)